<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
    <id>org.dpsoftware.FireflyLuciferin</id>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">org.dpsoftware.FireflyLuciferin.desktop</launchable>
    <name>Firefly Luciferin</name>
    <developer id="org.dpsoftware">
        <name>Davide Perini</name>
    </developer>
    <summary>Ambient lighting software</summary>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
    <url type="homepage">https://github.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin</url>
    <url type="help">https://github.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/wiki</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/issues</url>
    <url type="donation">https://www.paypal.com/donate?hosted_button_id=ZEJM8ZLQW5E4A</url>
    <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin</url>
    <branding>
        <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#ffae00</color>
        <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#7a4e00</color>
    </branding>
    <description>
        <p>Ambient Lighting or Bias Light is a technology that enhances your viewing experience by projecting colored lights onto the wall behind
            your TV/Monitor, matching the colors on the screen. This creates a more immersive and engaging atmosphere, making your favorite shows,
            movies, and games feel even more captivating.</p>
        <p>Luciferin is a generic term for the light-emitting compound found in organisms that generate bioluminescence like Fireflies and Glow Worms.
            Firefly Luciferin is a Java Fast Screen Capture PC software designed for Glow Worm Luciferin firmware,
            those two software create the perfect Bias Lighting and Ambient Light system for PC.
            Differently from other solutions, Firefly and Glow Worm Luciferin are designed to work together for the best experience possible.</p>
        <p>Key features</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Best in class performance combined with ultra low CPU/GPU usage.</li>
            <li>Advanced algorithms for smooth colors transitions and color correction. Seeing is believing.</li>
            <li>Wireless or cabled, local or remote? Choose your flavour with MQTT support and Home Assistant integration.</li>
            <li>Multi monitor support with single or multiple instances.</li>
            <li>Surround lighting with satellites.</li>
            <li>Web browser firmware installer and Web Interface.</li>
            <li>Programmable firmware, change your microcontroller's settings on the fly.</li>
            <li>Frequent updates, upgrade your PC software and your firmware in one click.</li>
            <li>Automatic switching between aspect ratios based on your video content.</li>
            <li>Made from a gamer, for gamers. No added lag, stutter free.</li>
            <li>Multi platform, Windows and Linux ready. macOS is coming when it's ready.</li>
            <li>If you don't want to design your own PCB and you have a soldering iron, there is Luciferin's official PCB.</li>
            <li>Have a question? Get answered on the community.</li>
        </ul>
    </description>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <caption>Bias light effect</caption>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/cc960fbef900471303c3ab1d10980ed1a8a57a7f/data/img/ambilight_color.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <caption>Luciferin UI</caption>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/08852270fe719b1c0ad2aaeade321118ecaa9b59/data/img/settings_1.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <caption>Luciferin UI</caption>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/08852270fe719b1c0ad2aaeade321118ecaa9b59/data/img/settings_2.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <caption>Luciferin UI</caption>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/08852270fe719b1c0ad2aaeade321118ecaa9b59/data/img/settings_3.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <caption>Web Interface</caption>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sblantipodi/glow_worm_luciferin/6c3184d5f8090d6009b81916d9ae6ba4c310fe00/assets/img/web_interface.jpg</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <caption>Home Assistant integration</caption>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sblantipodi/glow_worm_luciferin/a9931c31597edd6263b0c6769adf8398e29d9dd9/assets/img/HA_mobile_client_screenshot.jpg</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <caption>Test Image</caption>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/2a848b0161ec9f488c15af8036b131a4a8bcc0e5/data/img/testimage.jpg</image>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <releases>
        <release version="2.19.3" date="2024-12-18">
            <url type="details">https://github.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/releases/tag/v2.19.3</url>
            <description>
                <p>Breaking changes: requires Glow Worm Luciferin firmware (v5.18.2)</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The priority of UDP packets in wireless mode has been increased to signal to the router that
                        Luciferin traffic requires lower latency than standard packets.
                    </li>
                    <li>If the microcontroller is temporarily disconnected from the WiFi network, Firefly Luciferin is
                        now able to reconnect much faster without restarting the screen capture.
                    </li>
                    <li>Added a 'bottom' capture option for satellites when the LEDs are configured to use a bottom
                        gap.
                    </li>
                    <li>The feature for preserving settings after each restart has been restructured. Auto-save has been
                        disabled to prevent wear on the microcontroller's memory.
                    </li>
                    <li>libasound2t64 dependency prevents correct installation on some Linux distros.</li>
                    <li>Properly handle expired restore token on Wayland.</li>
                    <li>The snap version was crashing at startup when there were temporary files created by other instances of Firefly Luciferin on the system. Fixed.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.18.9" date="2024-12-18">
            <url type="details">https://github.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/releases/tag/v2.18.9</url>
            <description>
                <p>Breaking changes: requires Glow Worm Luciferin firmware (v5.17.8)</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Capture pipeline has been optimized for DX12 on Windows. Previously, under heavy GPU load, capture framerates would drop significantly, causing occasional LED stuttering. Now, the pipeline has been restructured to better utilize hardware resources, completely eliminating stuttering. This change, along with the previous SIMD extension released with the previous version of Firefly Luciferin, makes Luciferin one of the most optimized and fastest software for bias lighting available at the moment.</li>
                    <li>New effects and improvements to the existing ones.</li>
                    <li>Firefly Luciferin is now able to run on a Linux sandbox like Flatpak and Snap.</li>
                    <li>The response latency during Linux screen capture has been widely reduced.</li>
                    <li>Added a Tray icon and minimize to tray on Linux. Thanks @sorcererlc for the continued support.
                    </li>
                    <li>New non intrusive notification system on Linux.</li>
                    <li>The Info menu now displays the current CPU latency. Lower values indicate better performance.
                        This value can be influenced by your screen resolution, capture area dimensions, CPU/RAM
                        overclocking, and AVX extensions available on the CPU.
                    </li>
                    <li>Home Assistant: Luciferin entities are now grouped under one devices.</li>
                    <li>Update notifications are now less intrusive and no longer launch the update popup at computer startup. A simple notification informs about the available update, and you can proceed to install it by right-clicking on the tray icon and selecting 'install updates'.</li>
                    <li>Linux Wayland didn't ask you which screen to record when the recording permission expired.
                        Fixed.
                    </li>
                    <li>Power saving mode is not interrupted by small changes on the screen like icons changing state in the system tray or incoming notifications.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.17.13" date="2024-11-28">
            <url type="details">https://github.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/releases/tag/v2.17.6</url>
            <description>
                <p>Linux and Windows improvements</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Firefly Luciferin now supports Flatpak and is now available on Flathub.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.17.10" date="2024-11-25">
            <url type="details">https://github.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/releases/tag/v2.17.6</url>
            <description>
                <p>Linux and Windows improvements</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Firefly Luciferin now supports Flatpak and is now available on Flathub.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.9" date="2024-11-24">
            <url type="details">https://github.com/sblantipodi/firefly_luciferin/releases/tag/v2.17.6</url>
            <description>
                <p>Linux and Windows improvements</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Firefly Luciferin now supports Flatpak and is now available on Flathub.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
    </releases>
    <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
    <update_contact>perini.davide_at_dpsoftware.org</update_contact>
</component>
